Janmejay S Purohit

janmejayspurohit@gmail.com | +1 (929)-593-8209 | linkedin.com/in/jsp324 | janmejay.info

SUMMARY

I am currently pursuing Masters in Computer Science at Indiana University Bloomington and am actively seeking 2023-Summer internship opportunities. I have over 3 years of work experience as a full stack Javascript developer and am looking forward to pursue working in the same domain. My goal is to obtain a software developer position utilizing my strong programming skills and experience in developing, testing and implementing software solutions to improve efficiency and productivity for a company.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 2, Tesark Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Sep 2019 - Jul 2022

Started my career here as Software Engineer I, and worked on multiple projects primarily as a full stack Javascript developer. My main responsibilities included working with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance. I eventually was made responsible for researching and evaluating new technologies and software development methodologies, creating software development plans and schedules, leading software engineering teams and monitoring and optimizing software performance towards the end of my tenure.

Software Development Engineer Intern, Box8

Jan 2019 - Aug 2019

Extensively worked on API integrations with Ruby on Rails as the backend. Integrated various payment gateways like Google pay, Paytm, PhonePe. Worked on various bug fixes and improvements in the in-house application as well.

Software Engineer Intern, EzPG

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

Worked on PHP for application development, integrated features like search, sort, filter and manage hotel bookings.

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science Indiana University Bloomington Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering Dayananda Sagar University Aug 2022 - Present GPA: 3.9 Aug 2015 - May 2019 GPA: 9.21/10

PROJECTS

Smart Fish Tracking

Built a moving fish detection software on matlab that detects whether a fish is pregnant or not based on backgroud subtraction, linear regression and Kalman Filters. Based on the shape of the fish it promtps whether a fish is pregnant or not, which results in reduction of catching pregnant fishes during fishing. More details of this found my on my portfolio.

Image Steganography

Image steganography is the process of hiding one image or text, within another image, such that the presence of the hidden data is not visible to the human eye. As a developer working on this project, I was responsible for designing and implementing an application that can both hide and extract hidden data within cover images. This involved developing algorithms to encrypt and compress the hidden data and embed it into the cover image using XOR Encryption, as well as developing methods to detect and extract the hidden image from the cover image, using Matlab.

Vydhya

Worked on the front-end part of an engaging Patient Management System as part of my Software Engineering Course at IUB. A patient management system is a software application that helps healthcare providers store and track patient information, appointments, and medical records. As a front-end developer using React, my job was to design and develop the user interface for the system. This involved in creating and implementing user-friendly layouts, forms, and visual elements, as well as ensuring that the system is responsive and easy to navigate.

Portfolio Website

Build this portfolio to showcase my skills and abilities in web development, design, and user experience. I was responsible for designing and building the website from scratch, using technologies such as HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. I made sure to incorporate a visually appealing and user-friendly layout, and made sure the website is responsive and accessible across all devices. It also includes features such as contact form, about me section, resumes and links to your social media profiles.

SKILLS

Frameworks: NodeJS, ReactJS, NextJS, ExpressJS, AngularJS, Ruby on Rails, Django

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Python, Ruby, Java, C, C++

Software Packages: Jupyter Notebook, Postman, Git, Heroku, AWS - S3, EC2, RDS

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, MySQL